(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
これは、もうひとつの物語。
This is another story.
Sparkle Animelo Summer Live 2022
カレーメシ
Curry Meshi
SPECIAL OPENING ACT
hololive
諸君！カレーメシは好きか！？
Everyone! Do you like Curry Meshi!?
わたしは、カレーメシが大好きだ！
I love Curry Meshi!
カレーメシが好きだ！
ハヤシメシも好きだ！
I love Hayashi Meshi too!
キーマカレーメシも好きだ！
I love Keema Curry Meshi too!
カレーメシシーフードも好きだ！
I love Curry Meshi Seafood too!
ウマーメシも好きだ！
I love Uma-Meshi too!
オシャーメシも好きだ！
I love Osha-Meshi too!
日本で一番カレーメシが大好きだー！
I love Curry Meshi the most in Japan!
街中で！
In town!
森林で！
In the forest!
公園で！
In the park!
山頂で！
At the summit!
食卓で！
At the dining table!
部屋で！
In the room!
学校で！
At school!
職場で！
At work!
砂浜で！
On the beach!
キャンプで！
Camping!
お湯かけ5分でいつでもどこでもおいしいカレーが楽しめる！
You can enjoy delicious curry anytime, anywhere in 5 minutes with hot water!
世界で一番カレーメシが大好きだー！
I love Curry Meshi the most in the world!
諸君もカレーメシが大好きならば、
If you all love Curry Meshi too,
会場を黄金に染めてくれー！
please dye the venue in gold!
さあ諸君！スパイスラブの登場だ！
Now everyone! Here comes Spice Love!
お湯を入れて 指定のルール
Add hot water, follow the rules
混ぜろ 混ぜろ
Mix it, mix it
混ぜてとけたら カレーがドーン
Once mixed and melted, curry is done!
カレー カレー カレー カレー カレーメシでしょ (ハイ！)
Curry, curry, it's Curry Meshi, right? (Hi!)
めっちゃ！
Very!
カレーが食べたい でも配信直前
I want to eat curry, but it's right before a stream
これなんて大ピンチ 助けて (えー！)
This is a big pinch, help me! (Eh-!)
そんな私に 救世主登場 (マジで？)
A savior appears for me (Really?)
黄色のあいつがヒーローさ
That yellow guy is the hero
カレー カレー カレー カレー カレーメシでしょ (イェーイ！)
Curry, curry, it's Curry Meshi, right? (Yay!)
カレー カレー カレー カレー カレーメシ参上 (オカエー！)
Curry, curry, Curry Meshi is here (Welcome back!)
お湯を入れて (フー！)
Add hot water (Hoo!)
たった5分で (フー！)
In just 5 minutes (Hoo!)
本当に 本当に カレーなんて作れるの？
Can you really, really make curry?
フタをあけて (カレー！)
Open the lid (Curry!)
シャバシャバでも (大丈夫！)
Even if it's watery (It's okay!)
混ぜろ 混ぜろ ひたすら混ぜろ
Mix it, mix it, just keep mixing it
混ぜろ 混ぜろ
Mix it, mix it
本当にカレーになってきた！
It's really turning into curry!
イッツア ミラクル くるくるくる 日・新・カレーメシ
It's a miracle, round and round, Nis-shin Curry Meshi
レッツ ミラクル くるくるくる おい・しい・カレーメシ
Let's miracle, round and round, deli-cious Curry Meshi
イッツア ミラクル くるくるくる ほら・おい・しい (ハイ！)
It's a miracle, look, it's tasty (Hi!)
レッツ ミラクル くるくるくる あた・らしい・カレーの新時代
Let's miracle, a new era of curry
スパイス詰め込んだ (オーオーオオー)
Packed with spices (Oh oh oh oh)
こだわりの味 (オーオーオオー)
Particular taste (Oh oh oh oh)
大満足さ 日清 (ショー！ ショー！) 日新カレーメシ
Total satisfaction, Nisshin (Show! Show!) Nisshin Curry Meshi
シュバっと作れてウマいっすなー！
You can make it quickly and it's tasty!
カレーでこういうことぺこよー！
This is what curry is all about, peko!
普通に美味しいよ！
It's simply delicious!
みんなで！ カレーメシ！
Everyone! Curry Meshi!
即席とは思えないほど コクのある (フミフミ フミフミ)
So rich you wouldn't believe it's instant (Fumi-fumi)
味のバリエーションも豊富だから いつまでも 無限に行けちゃう
With so many flavor variations, you can go on forever
カレー カレー カレー カレー カレーメシでしょ (ハイ！)
Curry, curry, it's Curry Meshi, right? (Hi!)
カレー カレー カレー カレー カレーメシ参上 (オカエー！)
Curry, curry, Curry Meshi is here (Welcome back!)
電子レンジも (ノー！) お鍋もいらない (ノー！)
No microwave (No!), no pot needed either (No!)
本当に 本当にお湯だけ入れれば大丈夫
Really, really, it's okay just adding hot water
即席食品の てっぺん目指し
Aiming for the top of instant foods
混ぜろ 混ぜろ ひたすら混ぜろ 混ぜろ 混ぜろ
Mix it, mix it, just keep mixing it, mix it, mix it
混ぜろの時代がきたー！
The era of mixing has come!
イッツア ミラクル くるくるくる 日・新・カレーメシ
It's a miracle, round and round, Nis-shin Curry Meshi
レッツ ミラクル くるくるくる おい・しい・カレーメシ
Let's miracle, round and round, deli-cious Curry Meshi
イッツア ミラクル くるくるくる サイ・コー・感じちゃう君以外
It's a miracle, feeling the best, besides you
レッツ ミラクル くるくるくる たま・ねぎの・旨味
Let's miracle, the umami of onions
革新的な (オーオーオオー)
Innovative (Oh oh oh oh)
止まらない美味しさが (イエス！ イエス！)
Non-stop deliciousness (Yes! Yes!)
日新カレーメシ
Nisshin Curry Meshi
最先端のカレーでございます
This is state-of-the-art curry
そうさ ミラクル くるくるくる 日・新・カレーメシ
That's right, miracle, round and round, Nis-shin Curry Meshi
もっと ミラクル くるくるくる ガッ・ショウ・いただきます！
More miracle, round and round, Chorus! Let's eat!
イッツア ミラクル くるくるくる 日・新・カレーメシ
It's a miracle, round and round, Nis-shin Curry Meshi
レッツ ミラクル くるくるくる おい・しい・カレーメシ
Let's miracle, round and round, deli-cious Curry Meshi
N・I・S
N-I-S
S・I・N
S-I-N
カレーめし信者だい！
We're Curry Meshi believers!
本格派のルゥに (Wow Wow Wow)
With authentic roux (Wow Wow Wow)
国産米100％で (Wow Wow Wow)
And 100% domestic rice (Wow Wow Wow)
大満足不可避でしょ (しょ！しょ！)
Great satisfaction is inevitable (Right! Right!)
日清カレーめし
Nissin Curry Meshi
カレー・カレー・カレー・カレー・カレーめしでしょ
Curry, curry, curry, curry, Curry Meshi, right?
皆さん、こんにちはー！
Hello everyone!
こんにちはー！
Hello!
たくさんお客さんが来てる、嬉しいー！
So many guests are here, I'm happy!
ねー、本当にすごいペコ！
Yeah, it's really amazing, peko!
みんな来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you everyone for coming!
たまりだよー！
It's overwhelming!
嬉しいペコ！
I'm happy, peko!
すごーい！
Amazing!
さあ、ということで「カレーめし in アニサマライブ」
Now, that was 'Curry Meshi in Animelo Summer Live'.
披露させていただいたのは
We performed the
日清カレーめしとホロライブの
コラボレーションオリジナル楽曲、
Nissin Curry Meshi x Hololive
collaboration original song,
「カレーめし in ミラクル」でした！
'Curry Meshi in Miracle'!
はーい、お湯かけ5分で
Yes, just add hot water and wait 5 minutes...
いつでも、どこでも
Anytime, anywhere,
美味しいカレーが楽しめる、
日清カレーめしさんの提供でお届けする
you can enjoy delicious curry. Brought to you
by Nissin Curry Meshi,
こちらのスペシャルオープニングアクトを
務めさせていただくのは、
performing this special opening act is...
VTuber事務所ホロライブ所属、
カレーめしコラボレーションユニット、
Hololive's Curry Meshi collaboration unit,
スパイスラブです！
Spice Love!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！今日は日清カレーめしさん
からのミッションで、
Nice to meet you! Today, on a mission
from Nissin Curry Meshi,
このさいたまスーパーアリーナを
温めに来ました！
we came to warm up Saitama Super Arena!
イェーイ！いやー、ねー！
まさかアニサマの初日、
Yay! No way, right? On the first day of Anisama,
たくさんのアーティストさんに先駆けて、
ahead of so many other artists,
なんと、トップバッターいただきました！
we actually got to be the opening act!
いや、これも日清カレーめしさんやホロライブを
応援してくれるみんなのおかげで、
This is all thanks to everyone who supports
Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive,
この舞台に立つことができたペコ！って...
that we're able to stand on this stage, peko!
本当に会場広いペコねー！
The venue is really huge, peko!
やばいよね、マジで！
It's crazy, seriously!
ここにこれだけの人が集まるって本当にすごい
ことなんだなって改めて感じるよね。
Seeing so many people gathered here makes me
realize how amazing this is.
はい、ということで、ホロライブをご存じでない
お客様もいると思うので、
Since some of you may not know Hololive,
自己紹介したいと思います！
we'd like to introduce ourselves!
みんな準備いいですかー？
Everyone ready?
いきまーす！ホロライブ所属、
スパイスラブの黄色担当、
Here we go! Representing Hololive
and Spice Love in yellow,
大空スバル！今日はよろしくお願いします！
Oozora Subaru! Nice to meet you today!
はーい！皆さんどうもこんあくあー！
Yes! Hello everyone, Kon-aqua!
ホロライブ所属、スパイスラブのピンク担当、
湊あくあです！わーい！
Representing Hololive and Spice Love in pink,
I'm Minato Aqua! Yay!
こんぺこ、こんぺこ、こんぺこー！
Kon-peko, kon-peko, kon-peko!
ホロライブ所属、スパイスラブのブルー担当、
兎田ぺこらぺこ！よろぺこー！
Representing Hololive and Spice Love in blue,
I'm Usada Pekora, peko! Yoropeko!
はい、久しぶりに揃ったスパイスラブの3名が
務めるこのスペシャルオープニングアクトでは、
With Spice Love finally back together,
in this special opening act,
豪華なカレーめしライブステージを
背景にお送りしていきます！
we'll perform with this gorgeous
Curry Meshi live stage as our backdrop!
ということでね、知ってる人は知ってる、
So, for those of you who know it,
スバルが考案したスパイスラブの決めポーズ、
やっときますか？
shall we do the signature Spice Love pose
Subaru came up with?
あの例のアレぺこですね。
That one, right peko?
2年ぶりだよ、2年ぶり！
It's been two years!
そうだよ！真似ビシッと決めて
いきたいと思います。
That's right! I want us to get it perfectly.
ちょっと二人とも大丈夫？
Are you two okay?
はーい！ / 大丈夫！
Yes! / We're fine!
本当か？カメラさんもね、準備お願いします。
Really? Camera crew, please get ready too.
じゃあ行くよ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set!
スパイス・ラブ！
Spice Love!
覚えてる、覚えてる！
I remember it!
すごーい！カメラさんちゃんと撮れてますかこれ？
Amazing! Camera-san, did you get that?
やっぱこれ揃うといいね、可愛い！
It looks great when we're in sync, so cute!
いや、マジ3人の色合いが綺麗ペコだからね。
Yeah, the three colors really look beautiful together.
スパイスライブでお披露目して以来だから、
やっぱ嬉しいよねなんか揃うと。
It's been since the Spice Live reveal,
so it's nice to be in sync.
はい、そんなこんなで日清カレーめしさんとは
色々コラボレーションさせていただいております。
Anyway, we've been doing various
collaborations with Nissin Curry Meshi.
改めて、先ほど披露させていただいたのは、
Once again, the song we just performed was the
日清カレーめしとホロライブの
コラボレーションオリジナル楽曲、
Nissin Curry Meshi x Hololive
collaboration original song,
「カレーめし in ミラクル」でした！
'Curry Meshi in Miracle'!
昨年の2021年には地上波のゴールデンタイムで、
Last year, in 2021, during prime time TV,
日清カレーめしとホロライブによる
コラボレーションCMの楽曲としても使用されたペコ！
it was also used for the Nissin Curry Meshi
x Hololive collaboration CM, peko!
日清カレーメシは、お湯をかけて5分待つだけで
Nissin Curry Meshi, just add hot water and wait 5 minutes,
いつでもどこでも美味しいカレーを 食べることができて！
and you can enjoy delicious curry anytime, anywhere!
ライブの前とかに栄養補給とか、 ライブの後でも...
For a quick energy boost before a concert, or after a concert...
「あー、作りたくないなー」ってなった時！
when you think, "Ah, I don't want to cook anything!"
食べに行くのも面倒ってなった時、 ぴったりです！
When it's too much trouble to go out and eat, it's perfect!
うん！
Yeah!
会場に来てくれたみんなも、 この後のライブを目一杯楽しんだ後は、
Everyone here at the venue, after you enjoy the rest of today's concert to the fullest,
さいたまスーパーアリーナ近くの コンビニで絶賛発売中なので、
it's now on sale at convenience stores near Saitama Super Arena,
日清カレーメシを 食べながら今日のことを振り返ってほしいぺこ！
so I want you to reflect on today while eating Nissin Curry Meshi, peko!
日清カレーメシは バリエーションも豊富！
Nissin Curry Meshi comes in many varieties!
見かけたら是非いろんな味をね、 楽しんでほしいです！
If you see them, please enjoy all the different flavors!
今日のライブが終わったら 是非お買い求めください！
Please be sure to buy some after today's concert!
はーい！
Okay!
ということで、せっかくなので みんなに質問です！
So, since we're here, I have a question for everyone!
ライブが終わったらカレーメシ 食べてみようかなって人は、
If you're thinking of trying Curry Meshi after the concert,
カレー色のペンライトを上げて ほしいんだけど、いいですかー！？
I want you to raise your curry-colored penlights! Ready!?
よーし、じゃあみんなに質問するぞ！
Alright, then, here's the question for everyone!
ライブが終わったら カレーメシ食べたくなったかなー！？
Did you feel like eating Curry Meshi after the concert is over!?
はーい！
YES!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ということで、スバルたちの時間も 残すところわずか！
With that, Subaru and the others' time is almost up!
あっという間でしたが、 アニサマ本番前にこの曲を聴いてください！
It went by in a flash, but please listen to this song before the main Animelo Summer Live show begins!
みんなの夏は終わらない！
Everyone's summer won't end!
カレーメシとホロライブは これからも止まらない！
Curry Meshi and Hololive will never stop!
まだまだ行くぺこー！
We're still going, peko!
せーの！
One, two!
シャイニースマイリースーテーリー！
Shiny Smily Story!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to keep seeing the same future
あの夢 手にしたい
I want to grab that dream
それぞれ誓った
Each of us made a promise
心で
In our hearts
走り出そう
Let's start running
どこ見ても 真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
It sprouted in a place where everything seemed dark
ほんの小さな希望に
In just a tiny bit of hope
この瞳 奪われた
My eyes were captivated
不安で揺れる心を うまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart that wavers with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を
Gathering just a tiny bit of courage
振り絞っていたいよ
I want to muster it all up
あきらめの文字 デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward
苦しい時も もう私は
Even in tough times, I'm already...
一人じゃないから
no longer alone
だからもっと 夢 追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
空を越えてく
Going beyond the sky
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show the whole world
アクセスしてみてほしい
I want you to try and access it
後悔なんて そう させない
I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ誓った
Each of us made a promise
心で
In our hearts
走り出そう
Let's start running
彩れ
Color it in
理想の空に輝く 眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the ideal sky
見たことのない光を
Are a light never seen before
リアルに届けるよ
And I'll deliver them to you for real
いつも聞こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を
Looking for a new light
探したくなるよ
once again
君の笑顔は 保存して進む
Saving your smile and moving forward
悲しい時に 見返すよ
I'll look back at it when I'm sad
力が湧くから
Because it gives me strength
胸を張って 夢 追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with pride
奇跡のストーリー
A story of miracles
一緒に作ろう
Let's make it together
終わらない夢を
In this never-ending dream
誰一人 欠かせない
Not a single person is expendable
アイが待った この世界
In this world where love awaits
それぞれ誓った
Each of us made a promise
心で
In our hearts
彩れ
Color it in
悲しい時も 寂しい時も
When you're sad or lonely
信じ合えるものがある
There's something we can believe in together
忘れずに この鼓動
Don't forget, this heartbeat...
鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep it beating
終わらない世界に
Into an endless world
溢れ出すよ
Overflowing
笑顔たちが
With smiles
憧れの舞台 立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage I've longed for
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine as myself
時に涙して
Sometimes shedding tears
また笑い合いたい
I want to laugh together again
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢 手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出すよ 奇跡の
Taking a step
一歩を
Toward a miracle
息切らして 夢追いかけた
Out of breath, I chased my dreams
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement is unstoppable
想像を超えてく
Going beyond imagination
世界 見せてあげる
I'll show you the world
アクセスしてみない？
Why don't you try connecting?
後悔なんて ここにない
There are no regrets here
それぞれ違う
With each of our different
心で
Hearts
作る輪！
We'll create a circle!
Sparkle
ANIMELO SUMMER LIVE 2022